<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>khalid.se</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/</link>
    <description>Recent content on khalid.se</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.142.0</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 06 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Be inspired or be DESTROYED - daily wholesomeness in your terminal</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2024-07-06_get_inspired/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2024-07-06_get_inspired/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Following this guide, you&amp;rsquo;ll have the latest wholesome mastodon post printed when you open your shell.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Be inspired or be DESTROYED!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;prerequisites&#34;&gt;Prerequisites&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The following applications must be present on the system and in your $PATH:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;curl&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;jq&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;fetching-statuses-from-the-terminal&#34;&gt;Fetching statuses from the terminal&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since the response from Mastodon is delivered as a JSON-array, having &lt;code&gt;jq&lt;/code&gt; installed will help greatly with parsing the content. Mastodon has support for alt-text on images, and the user &lt;code&gt;@skeletor@mas.to&lt;/code&gt; is kind enough to provide that with each posted image which makes it trivial to fetch the latest wholesome inspirational quote, even though the quote is images with text. This is accomplished by the following command:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chako paul city and the spread of disinformation</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2023-10-15_chako_paul_city/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2023-10-15_chako_paul_city/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Do you remember the tale of 25,000 lesbian lumberjacks living together in northern Sweden? Chako Paul City, as the story goes, was guarded with an iron resolve to prevent any men from entering the city. Those daring enough to try were beaten to death, while any woman returning to the city had to undergo a ceremonial wash before reentry.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This was, of course, utter nonsense.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This story was fabricated by a journalist from the newspaper &lt;em&gt;Xinhuanet&lt;/em&gt;. To be clear, this was not intended as a satirical piece. This story took on a life of its own, rapidly spreading like wildfire leading leading to Swedish tourism websites crashing and causing internet service providers in China to grind to a halt due to the flood of traffic.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A few hours of running a honeypot</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2023-09-06_honeypot/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2023-09-06_honeypot/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I often come across various communities that strongly encourage people to self-host for a variety of reasons: in the interest of data sovereignty, to break free from big tech, or simply because it&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href=&#34;https://dwarffortresswiki.org/DF2014:Fun&amp;amp;redirect=no&#34;&gt;&amp;ldquo;FUN&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a&gt;. However, I believe that many of these encouragements do not take into account the risks associated with running your infrastructure, nor do they take into account the competence required to correctly configure specific products, systems, applications so that they can provide a secure solution. And if you can&amp;rsquo;t accomplish this (or if you run outdated, vulnerable software), you might end up with an entry point in your setup, allowing an outsider to gain access to your server. Moreover, without the ability to respond promptly 24/7, you may not be able to react in a timely manner — assuming you&amp;rsquo;ve even set up some kind of intrusion detection.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cybersecurity basics, 2023 edition</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2023-08-03_cybersecurity_for_activists/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2023-08-03_cybersecurity_for_activists/</guid>
      <description>&lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;img loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;../../images/2023-08-03_cybersecurity_for_activists.png&#34;
         alt=&#34;Picture from the seminar at Stockholm Pride House.&#34;/&gt; &lt;figcaption&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Picture from the seminar at Stockholm Pride House.&lt;/p&gt;
        &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today, I had the pleasure of discussing cybersecurity with 30 enthusiastic attendees at Stockholm Pride House who defied the rain and the risk of getting wet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve conducted this seminar since 2020. At the height of the pandemy, I noticed a sharp rise in the need for cybersecurity as more and more individuals had to communicate and collaborate digitally due to the pandemic. These seminars is provided to level the playing field between those advocating for human rights and their antagonists who typically possess far more resources in terms of offensive cyber capabilities.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>About me</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Jul 2023 19:34:34 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/about/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I am an IT and security manager at an international NGO in Sweden, and this is where I publish works of intrest and do some crazy experimentation behind the scenes. As I don&amp;rsquo;t participate in big tech social media, this is where I have my presence. This site is not and will not be monetized.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;topics-that-i-engage-with&#34;&gt;Topics that I engage with&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Health and well-being&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sustainable living&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Digital privacy and sovereignty&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-im-not-doing-now&#34;&gt;What I&amp;rsquo;m &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; doing now&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As much as I like the idea of having a &lt;a href=&#34;https://nownownow.com/about&#34;&gt;now page&lt;/a&gt;, it&amp;rsquo;s not feasible for me. Instead, I can tell you what I&amp;rsquo;m not doing now:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Are endusers really the weakest link?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2023-02-05_weakest_link/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2023-02-05_weakest_link/</guid>
      <description>&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve recently started a cybersecurity course in university and got very engaged by an assignment where I was to make a list on how to reduce the human factor when dealing with cyber security, and wrote these thoughts.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’d like to delve deeper into an idea within cybersecurity professionals that “a chain is only as strong as its weakest link” that often is pointingat  the end-users as that weakest link (1). After the article “In Defence of the Human Factor“ (2), and following the latest discourse in the cybersec community, I&amp;rsquo;d like to challenge the idea of end-users being the weakest link.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
